Suhwa Lee

User Experience designer

-

Jan evertsenstraat 637 1061XZ Amsterdam The Netherlands

suhwa.christina.lee@gmail.com

+31 (0)657773812

Summary

I am a User Experience designer and a design thinker.

I have a strong skill in connecting the dots -user research results, data, and business requirements- and translating into design concepts. I am also an enthusiastic maker. I create tangible interactions and prototypes to experimentdesign concepts with the users. I endeavor to bring good design to life by understanding people and connecting digital experience with real-life experiences.

Experience

Interaction Designer at IceMobile

October 2016 - Present

I am currently working on a retailer application for one of the biggest retailer in Russia. I have been working on various mobile applications in the high-frequence retail industry. A short list of what i do includes; user research, prototyping, user testing, wireframes to realize concept to product and tag plans to access the usability after software releases.

-

User Experience Designer at ABN AMRO Bank N.V.

June 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 2 months)

I worked on a Mobile banking app of ABN Amro, one of the biggest banks in the Netherlands. I worked in a scrum product development team where we constantly bring values to the users through the app which people use on a daily basis. The design and development were data-driven. My role involved concept design, data-driven design, design research, prototyping and usability test.

-

Graduating Intern, User Experience at Designit

July 2015 - December 2015 (6 months)

During my internship at Designit, I was collaborating with Designit on my master thesis: Smartphone controlled home environments. The project sought to integrate gesture control in smart living context especially at home environments and resulted in a gesture control library for a smartphone to control the home environments and the smartphone itself.

-

User Experience Designer Intern at LUNAR Europe GmbH

March 2014 - August 2014 (6 months)

I was involved in various projects in Lunar Europe, which includes product design, interaction design, graphic design, and print design. My biggest achievement during the internship would be a world clock application: Onetime, which shows different time zones in on one clock, which is beautifully visualized based on the sun and earth's movement.

-

Student Volunteer at IxDA 2014 Education Summit

February 2014 - February 2014 (1 month)

I took part in Interaction Design Association (IxDA) 2014 Education summit as a student volunteer. My tasks were to prepare and participate in workshops of the event. To initiate one of the workshops in the event, I created a

provocative movie clip in collaboration with another student, about 'Online presence and portfolios', which explored the qualities that a good interaction design portfolio should have and how are these can be best presented using online/offline platforms.

_

UI/UX Designer Intern at Moglue

December 2010 - June 2011 (7 months)

I worked as a UI/UX Design intern to help the company to establish their Brand and Corporate Identity (BI/CI), and to develop Moglue, a graphic software for interactive e-book creation and publication.

Education

Delft University of Technology

February 2013 - March 2016 (3 years 2 months) Master of Science (MS), Design for Interaction, 2013 - 2015 TU Delft Excellence Scholarship (Full scholarship) Recipient

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Industrial Design, 2008 - 2013

-

RMIT University

Exchange student, Industrial and Product Design, 2011 - 2011

Honors & Awards

Winner Spark! award: Digital

Jul 2015, The Spark 9th Annual International Awards

Onetime, a world clock that integrates all time zones into one beautiful easy-to-read dial was nominated as the winner in Spark:Digital competition, among 500 entrants from around the world.

_

TU Delft Excellence Scholarship (Health)

Sep 2014, The Delft University of Technology (TU Delft)

Delft Research-based Initiative Scholarship (Health) is a full scholarship (coverage of tuition fees and monthly allowance for living expenses), awarded to 4 new students each year. Excellent applicants admitted to one of TU Delft's MSc programmes with a with a cumulative grade point average (GPA) of 80 percent or higher of the scale maximum in your bachelor's degree from an internationally renowned university.

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency) **Korean** (Native)